In the last video,
在上个视频中
you learned about the efficient frontier.
我们介绍了有效边界
You know that any point on the efficient frontier represents
有效边界上的每个点
the portfolio that gives you the best risk return trade-off,
都代表最佳风险-收益率组合
and that these portfolios are known as market portfolios.
这些投资组合称为市场投资组合
But is that it? Is there a way to do better than the efficient frontier?
这样就行了吗？还有比有效边界更好的结果吗？
In this video, we will be adding a risk-free asset into
在本视频中 我们将向投资组合中添加一个无风险资产
our portfolio and we're going to introduce something called the capital market line.
并介绍一个概念 叫做资本市场线
A risk-free asset is an investment instrument that
无风险资产是指完全没有风险
entails absolutely no risk or uncertainty.
或没有不确定性的投资工具
In theory, if you invest in such an instrument,
从理论上讲 如果投资此类金融工具
you receive a guaranteed rate of return called the risk-free rate and
你将获得有保障的收益率 称为无风险利率
reality entirely risk-free assets don't
在现实中 不存在这样的无风险资产
exist since all investments carry a certain level of risk.
因为所有投资都存在一定的风险
However, in practice people normally refer to the rate of
但是 在现实中 人们通常将
return on a three month treasury bill as the risk-free rate.
三个月期国债利率称为无风险利率
Now let's add this risk-free asset into the picture.
下面将这个无风险资产添加到投资组合中
Let's imagine we construct a new portfolio with any of
假设我们创建了一个新的投资组合
the market portfolios that you prefer and the risk-free asset.
其中可以包含任何市场投资组合以及无风险资产
Which market portfolio would you choose?
你会选择哪个市场投资组合？
Note that this new portfolio is
注意 新的投资组合
a weighted sum of the risk-free asset and the market portfolio.
是无风险资产和市场投资组合的加权和
For example, if you choose the green portfolio as your market portfolio and the red.
例如 如果你选择将绿色投资组合作为市场投资组合
as your risk-free asset,
并将红点作为无风险资产
the line between them represents
那么二者之间的线条表示
the potential portfolios that you can construct with the two assets.
你可以使用这两个资产构建的潜在投资组合
Now, which market portfolio would you choose
对于给定的风险水平
so as to achieve the best return for a given level of risk?
如果要获得最佳收益率 你会选择哪个市场投资组合？
Well, you should be looking at the efficient frontier,
或许应该重点看看有效边界
the top edge of the set of possible portfolios.
即潜在投资组合集合的上边缘
It turns out that you should choose the market portfolio that allows you to draw
实际上 你应该选择一个特定的市场投资组合
a straight line starting from
使你能够从无风险资产
the risk-free asset that just touches the top of the efficient frontier.
画一条切过有限边界上边缘的直线
To see why this is the best market portfolio for the job,
为了解释为何这个是最佳市场投资组合
let's take a look at lines A, B,
我们来看看直线 A B 和 C
and C. Note that line A connects
直线 A 将
the red dot which represents the risk-free asset with the green dot,
表示无风险资产的红点
which represents the tangent market portfolio on the efficient frontier.
与表示有效边界上的切点市场投资组合的绿点相连
Line A lies above the efficient frontier and intersects the tangent portfolio.
直线 A 在有效边界上 与切点投资组合相交
All the portfolios represented by line A have higher returns
在相同的风险水平下
than the ones on the efficient frontier given the same risk level.
直线 A 表示的所有投资组合的收益率比有效边界上的点都高
This is not the case for lines B and
直线 B 和 C 并不这样
C. Portfolios on this tangent line are the best achievable.
这条切线上的投资组合是能达到的最佳投资组合
They even beat the efficient frontier which consists of purely risky assets.
甚至打败了完全包含有风险资产的有效边界
This line is called the capital market line.
这条线称为资本市场线
Now what is the expected return of
包含有风险投资组合
the portfolio consisting of the risky portfolio and the risk-free asset?
以及无风险资产的投资组合的预期收益率是多少？
The formula for this quantity is also the formula for
这个收益率的公式也是资本市场线的公式
the capital market line because each point on this line
因为这条线上的每个点
gives the return as a function of risk of
将收益率表示成
a possible combination of the risky portfolio and the risk-free asset.
有风险投资组合与无风险资产的潜在组合的风险函数
So let's examine the graph to determine the equation.
我们通过该图表判断方程是什么
You have two points 0,
有两个点
rf which is the risk-free portfolio and sigma m,
(0,r_f) 表示无风险投资组合
rm which is the market portfolio.
(σ_M,r_m) 表示市场投资组合
The slope of a line simply equals rm minus rf divided by sigma m.
这条线的斜率等于 (r_M - r_f)/σ_M
This quantity the difference between the market return and
这个值 即市场收益率与无风险利率之间的差
the risk-free rate is called the market risk premium.
称为市场风险溢价
The portfolio return is then just the risk-free rate of return as
投资组合收益率等于无风险收益率（基准）
a baseline plus the slope times the portfolio volatility.
加上斜率乘以投资组合波动率
The portfolio volatility will depend on what weights you choose to
投资组合波动率取决于
put on the risk-free asset and the market portfolio, i.e.
你对无风险资产和市场投资组合设定的权重
where you choose to sit along the capital market line.
也就是你要选择哪个资本市场线位置
The slope of the capital market line,
资本市场线的斜率是一个特殊的量
which is of course the same for all points on
称为市场夏普比率
the line is a special quantity known as the Sharpe Ratio of the market.
当然 这条线上的所有点斜率是一样的
We're going to discuss that more in a future lesson.
我们将在后面的课程中讨论夏普比率
In fact, if you can borrow at the risk-free rate,
实际上 如果能够以无风险利率借入资金
you can achieve points on
那么可以达到资本市场线
the capital market line to the right of the tangent market portfolio.
切点右侧的点
This amounts to setting a negative weight on the risk-free asset.
相当于对无风险资产设置负权重
That is to say, shorting it.
也就是做空
This is why professional investors care almost only about
这就是为何专业投资者几乎只关心夏普比率
the Sharpe ratio because they can manufacture any level of risk or return with leverage.
因为他们能够通过杠杆作用产生任何水平的风险或收益率